April Denise Johnson

Waldorf, MD ● 434-549-2355 ● aprildjohnson1@gmail.com *Active Top Secret Security Clearance*

Professional Summary

Resourceful Help Desk Supervisor with 10 years of experience in customer service and troubleshooting issues for digital collaboration tool used by the Navy. Adept at giving detailed and patient instructions. Successful at training employees and ensuring excellent customer service. I am a driven professional pursuing opportunities in the field of computer information systems and information technology. Specific interests include cybersecurity, database administration and system administration with a business focus.

Skills

- Teamwork and Collaboration
- Data Entry
- Application Support
- Training and Development

- Support Ticket System Management
- Problem-Solving
- System Performance Testing
- Technical Troubleshooting

Work Experience

Program Analyst/IT Helpdesk Supervisor (January 2018- Present) **SimVentions,** Dahlgren, VA

- Provided technical support to customers by handling systems-related issues; provide on-call technical support via phone and email
- Performed troubleshooting to isolate and diagnose common system problems
- Implemented and documents processes and procedures to ensure compliance with standard business practices
- Assisted in the implementation of training tools and documentation
- Provided technical consultation on current and proposed systems to other organizations and clients
- Assisted in the analysis and resolve program support deficiencies and conducts testing to enhance performance
- Performed quality assurance to meet appropriate standards and facilitated the improvement of processes
- Recorded and edited videos to facilitate remote learning of Windchill Software
- Collected, organized, and modeled data using Windchill Software
- Prepared and presented learning material to support the Windchill Software
- Tested software remotely and onsite for server sets to maintain operational readiness

Systems Administrator (October 2012- January 2018)

CSRA, Washington, DC

- Provided technical support to customers by handling systems-related issues; provide on-call technical support telephonically and electronically
- Performed troubleshooting to isolate and diagnose common system problems
- Implemented and documented processes and procedures to ensure compliance with standard business practices
- Assisted in the implementation of training tools and documentation
- Provided technical consultation on current and proposed systems to other organizations and clients
- Assisted in the analysis and resolve program support deficiencies and conducts testing to enhance performance
- Processed documentation and provide training for account access

Executive Assistant (July 2010- October 2012)

Computer Sciences Corporation (CSC), Washington, DC

- Provided support to Vice President of Advance Marine Center by scheduling and maintaining calendar of appointments, and meetings, scheduling internal meetings
- Prioritized and managed multiple tasks simultaneously, and follow through on issues in a timely manner
- Prepared reports for weekly staff meetings by obtaining, assembling, and analyzing information and data from Directorates
- Greeted arriving visitors, determined nature and purpose of visit and directed individuals to appropriate destinations.
- Filed paperwork and organized computer-based information.
- Processed travel expenses and reimbursements for executive team and senior management group.
- Responded to emails and other correspondence to facilitate communication and enhance business processes.
- Scheduled appointments and handled calendars for senior leadership.
- Coordinated and booked airfare, hotel and ground transportation and prepared itinerary to facilitate successful trips.

Business Analyst (November 2009- July 2010)

Computer Sciences Corporation (CSC), Washington, DC

- Created retained and referenced files; provided analytical support and monitored task management
- Assisted the Test and Evaluation (T&E) Department in analyzing and documenting client's business requirements; assisted and interfaced with department support technical personnel
- Organized department level meetings with clients, created customer requirement binders; reviewed planned tests objectives prior to schedule tasks

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Information Systems 05/2009

Virginia State University – Petersburg, VA

Certifications

CompTIA Security+ Certified Professional